<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter annotations="" version="5.0" xml:id="glossary"
         xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
         xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema"
         xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:ns5="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
         xmlns:ns4="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"
         xmlns:ns3="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
         xmlns:ns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
  <glossary>
    <title>Spring actionscript Glossary</title>

    <para>This is a list of terms used throughout the Spring Actionscript
    documentation.</para>

    <glossdiv>
      <title>C</title>

      <glossentry xml:id="Cairngorm">
        <glossterm>Cairngorm</glossterm>

        <glossdef>
          <para>Cairngorm is the lightweight micro-architecture for Rich Internet Applications built in Flex or AIR. A collaboration of recognized design patterns, Cairngorm exemplifies and encourages best-practices for RIA development advocated by Adobe Consulting, encourages best-practice leverage of the underlying Flex framework, while making it easier for medium to large teams of software engineers deliver medium to large scale, mission-critical Rich Internet Applications.</para>
        </glossdef>
      </glossentry>
    </glossdiv>

    <glossdiv>
      <title>D</title>

      <glossentry>
        <glossterm>DI</glossterm>

        <glosssee otherterm="DI" />
      </glossentry>

      <glossentry xml:id="DI">
        <glossterm>Dependency injection</glossterm>

        <abbrev>DI</abbrev>

        <glossdef>
          <para>Dependency Injection (DI) in computer programming refers to the process of supplying an external dependency to a software component. It is a specific form of inversion of control where the concern being inverted is the process of obtaining the needed dependency. The term was first coined by Martin Fowler to more clearly describe the mechanism.</para>

          <glossseealso otherterm="IoC" />
        </glossdef>
      </glossentry>
    </glossdiv>

    <glossdiv>
      <title>E</title>

      <glossentry xml:id="xml">
        <glossterm>Extensible Markup Language</glossterm>

        <acronym>XML</acronym>

        <glossdef>
          <para>XML (Extensible Markup Language) is a general-purpose specification for creating custom markup languages.</para>

          <glossseealso otherterm="xml" />
        </glossdef>
      </glossentry>
    </glossdiv>

    <glossdiv>
      <title>I</title>

      <glossentry>
        <glossterm>IoC</glossterm>

        <glosssee otherterm="IoC" />
      </glossentry>

      <glossentry xml:id="IoC">
        <glossterm>Inversion of Control</glossterm>

        <abbrev>IoC</abbrev>

        <glossdef>
          <para>Inversion of Control, or IoC, is an abstract principle describing an aspect of some software architecture designs in which the flow of control of a system is inverted in comparison to the traditional architecture of software libraries.</para>

          <glossseealso otherterm="DI" />
        </glossdef>
      </glossentry>

      <glossentry xml:id="IDE">
        <glossterm>Integrated development environment</glossterm>

        <abbrev>IDE</abbrev>

        <glossdef>
          <para>An integrated development environment (IDE) also known as integrated design environment or integrated debugging environment is a software application that provides comprehensive facilities to computer programmers for software development.</para>
        </glossdef>
      </glossentry>
    </glossdiv>

    <glossdiv>
      <title>P</title>

      <glossentry xml:id="PureMVC">
        <glossterm>PureMVC</glossterm>

        <glossdef>
          <para>PureMVC is a lightweight framework for creating applications based upon the classic Model, View and Controller concept. Based upon proven design patterns, this free, open source framework which was originally implemented in the ActionScript 3 language for use with Adobe Flex, Flash and AIR, is now being ported to all major development platforms.</para>
        </glossdef>
      </glossentry>
    </glossdiv>

    <glossdiv>
      <title>X</title>

      <glossentry xml:id="XML">
        <glossterm>XML</glossterm>

        <glosssee otherterm="xml" />
      </glossentry>
    </glossdiv>
  </glossary>
</chapter>
